- Imagine your boss says to you, "We need to talk."
-想像你的老闆對你說：「我們需要談談。」
A little worrying, right?
有點擔心，對吧？
Now, imagine a coworker says, "We need to talk."
現在，想像一位同事說：「我們需要談談。」
Same words, different reaction.
相同的話，不同的反應。
You can sense the difference between those situations
您可以感覺到這些情況之間的區別
because you understand nuance, context and consequences
，因為您了解細微差異，上下文
but AI can't understand those things,
和後果，但人工智能無法理解這
not on its own at least.
些事情，至少不單獨理解。
It can be an amazing collaborator
它可以是一個很棒的合作
and help you enhance your work in all sorts of ways
夥伴，並以各種方式幫助您提高工作，
but AI doesn't live in the real world like we do.
但 AI 並不像我們一樣生活在現實世界中。
That means you need to exercise responsible AI use.
這意味著您需要執行負責任的 AI 使用。
This is a big part of our work here at Google.
這是我們在 Google 工作的重要部分。
We're committed to AI that encourages bold innovation,
我們致力於推動人工智慧，鼓勵大膽創新、負
responsible development and collaborative progress.
責任的發展和協作進步。
These are AI principles.
這些是 AI 原則。
So knowing AI's limitations
因此，了解 AI 的限制
enables you to use it more effectively and responsibly.
使您能夠更有效和負責任地使用它。
For example, AI can get things wrong
例如，AI 可能會發現錯誤，
and say things that aren't true or suddenly false.
並說出不正確或突然是錯誤的事情。
This is called hallucination.
這被稱為幻覺。
There are many reasons why AI may hallucinate.
AI 可能會產生幻覺的原因有很多。
For one, it may be that its underlying training data
首先，可能是它的基礎訓練數據
has an error.
有錯誤。
It could also be that it's trying to solve a problem
也可能是因為它試圖解決一
that's entirely too unique and that it hasn't seen before.
個完全太獨特且以前沒有見過的問題。
Might also struggle to accurately understand
可能也很難準確地理
real world knowledge and physical things
解現實世界知識和物
or it might be because it's trying to create an answer
理事物，或者可能是因為它試圖創造答
but it's really just a guess.
案，但這實際上只是猜測。
Because AI can hallucinate,
因為人工智能可能會產生幻
you always need to pay attention and verify what you get
覺，因此您始終需要注意並驗證您在工作中
before using it in your work,
使用它在工作中獲得的內容，
even if the responses sound confident.
即使回應聽起來很有信心。
Another limitation you should be aware of
您應該注意的另一個
is that AI does not have common sense like you and me.
限制是 AI 沒有像您和我一樣具有常識。
And while its outputs can seem insightful or intuitive,
雖然它的輸出可能看起來有洞察力或直
you have to remember
觀，但您必
that it doesn't have a real understanding of the world.
須記住它對世界沒有真正的理解。
At the end of the day,
最終，它的
its outputs are just based on patterns it learned from data,
輸出只是基於它從數據中學到的模式，而
not real experience.
不是真實的經驗。
For instance, recently, I asked it about street festivals
例如，最近，我問了它關於即將到來的
in an upcoming weekend.
週末的街頭節日。
It pulled street festivals from previous years.
它吸引了過去幾年的街頭節日。
It was a mistake but I caught it and corrected it.
這是一個錯誤，但我抓到它並修正了它。
So what part do you play as an AI user?
那麼，作為 AI 用戶，您扮演什麼角色？
Well, you're in the driver's seat.
好吧，你坐在駕駛座位。
You're responsible for overseeing each step of the process
您負責監督程序的每個步驟，
from beginning to end.
從開始到結束。
We call this human-in-the-loop
我們稱這個人為循環中的人類，
meaning you should be constantly involved
這意味著您應該在每個步
with the use of AI at each step.
驟中不斷參與 AI 的使用。
Now, the need to use AI responsibly is pretty obvious
現在，負責任地使用 AI 的需要很明
but you may be thinking to yourself,
顯，但您可能會想：
"How do I do this," or "Where do I start?"
「我該如何做到這一點」或「我該從哪裡開始？」
Well, there are three simple steps
好吧，有三個簡單的步驟
to making sure you're using AI responsibly.
可以確保您負責任地使用 AI。
To remember it, we like to use the term ACT
為了記住這一點，我們喜歡以負責任的方式使
for ACT responsibly.
用 ACT 一詞代表 ACT。
A stands for ask.
A 代表詢問。
Before doing anything, ask yourself,
在做任何事情之前，請
"Is this even a case where I should be using AI?"
問自己：「這是我應該使用 AI 的情況嗎？」
For example, don't rely on responses as medical,
例如，不要依賴回應作為醫療、法
legal, financial or other professional advice.
律、財務或其他專業建議。
Always consult a professional on these topics.
始終就這些主題諮詢專業人士。
If your task involves sensitive,
如果您的任務涉及敏
confidential, personal or proprietary data,
感、機密、個人或專有資料，
consider whether or not you should use AI.
請考慮是否應該使用 AI。
Another question you should ask yourself is,
您應該問自己的另一個問題
"Can I use an off the shelf solution,"
是：「我可以使用現成的解決方案
or "Is it better suited for an enterprise tool?"
嗎？」或「它是否更適合企業工具？」
You should always consult your employer's policies
您應始終諮詢雇主在工作中
on using AI at work
使用 AI 的政策，
and avoid inputting confidential data into a public AI tool.
並避免將機密數據輸入到公共 AI 工具中。
Next up, C which stands for check.
接下來，C 代表檢查。
After you've decided that AI is right for the task,
在您決定 AI 適合任務之後，請在
check the outputs before using them.
使用之前檢查輸出。
First, check for objectivity.
首先，檢查客觀性。
Remember that a model's training data
請記住，模型的訓練數據有
can sometimes produce unintended results.
時會產生意外的結果。
It's your responsibility
您的責任是
to critically review the AI's response.
批判性審查 AI 的回應。
This involves looking out for one-sided arguments,
這包括尋找
or other unfair assumptions that AI may have learned.
AI 可能學到的單面論據，加載的語言，刻型或其他不公平假設。
Next, check for accuracy.
接下來，檢查準確性。
Verify the outputs you receive
驗證您收到的輸出
and make sure that any information
，並確保所呈現為實
which is presented as factual actually is.
際的任何信息實際上都是。
When checking your outputs,
檢查輸出時，
you also wanna look out for bias.
您也想留意偏差。
In many cases,
在許多情況
it's what you do with the output that matters.
下，重要的是您對輸出做什麼。
You should always check
您應始終檢查
that the output is appropriate for its intended use.
輸出是否適合其預期用途。
You should not rely on AI to finish work for you
您不應該依賴 AI 在沒有監視的情況下為
without your oversight.
您完成工作。
Completing the task requires your judgment
完成任務需要您的判斷
and accountability.
和責任。
Finally, T stands for tell.
最後，T 代表告訴。
Being a responsible AI user
成為負責任的 AI 用戶
involves disclosing your use of it.
需要披露您對其使用。
Always be transparent about your use of AI.
始終對使用 AI 保持透明度。
One way that Google is helping to increase transparency
Google 幫助提高
of AI use is with SynthID,
AI 使用透明度的一種方法是使用 SynthID，這是
a new tool which adds digital watermarks
一種新工具，該工具將數字水印添加到
into AI-generated content like videos
AI 生成的內容（例如視頻）中，以
so the use of AI can be detected easily.
便輕鬆檢測 AI 的使用。
Okay, we've covered all parts of ACT.
好吧，我們已經涵蓋了 ACT 的所有部分。
Before you use AI, ask yourself
在使用 AI 之前，請問自己
whether or not the tool is right for the task,
該工具是否適合任務，在使用之前檢
check all AI-generated outputs before using them
查所有 AI 產生的輸出，
and when you do, tell people.
然後在使用它們時告訴人們。
And remember, it's up to you
請記住，每個步驟都取決
to be the human-in-the-loop at each step.
於您成為循環中的人。
Now you're ready to keep going.
現在，您已準備好繼續前進。